<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terminal</title>
    <link>https://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Terminal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 22:03:59 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>review of top 5 songs</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 22:03:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Summary
Album Context
What Am I Missing?
Let It Happen
Save My Life
summary bruh idek y im doing this to be honest i actually just dont want to do any work like im not gna ever talk about this its just sad 🫥 But anyway as as passionate Arts Centre Enjoyer here are my musical interpretations of my three favourite songs of the album in no particular order&amp;hellip; (if u want i can add more depends on how long ur reading attension span is)</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/static/img/album-cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cover&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#album-context&#34;&gt;Album Context&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-am-i-missing&#34;&gt;What Am I Missing?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#let-it-happen&#34;&gt;Let It Happen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#save-my-life&#34;&gt;Save My Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bruh idek y im doing this to be honest i actually just dont want to do any work like im not gna ever talk about this its just sad 🫥
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But anyway as as &lt;em&gt;passionate Arts Centre Enjoyer&lt;/em&gt; here are my &lt;em&gt;musical interpretations&lt;/em&gt; of my three  favourite songs of the album in no particular order&amp;hellip; (if u want i can add more depends on how long ur reading attension span is)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;all-opinions-are-my-own-and-if-you-disagree-go-cope-with-the-fact-that-youre-wrong&#34;&gt;(all opinions are my own and if you disagree go cope with the fact that you&amp;rsquo;re wrong)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;album-context&#34;&gt;Album Context&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The album &lt;strong&gt;In The Dark&lt;/strong&gt; released by &lt;strong&gt;The Band CAMINO&lt;/strong&gt; (August, 2023) reflects on past trauma, self-destructive behaviours and questioning of one&amp;rsquo;s own beliefs as the members reminise over previous relationships and their aftermaths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this album, they explore the stages of an ill-fated relationship from beginning to post-breakup, starting with
the initial high (quite literally through Novacaine and Last Man in the World), their inevitable breakdown (Same Page), the suffering, depression
and trauma they experience afterwards (as seen in songs such as Three Month Hangover, Let It Happen and Afraid of the Dark) and eventually the acceptance of the past and even realisation of the difficulties throughout the relationship (It&amp;rsquo;s You (It&amp;rsquo;s You) and Told You So).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be said that although for a large portion of the album they are &amp;lsquo;In The Dark&amp;rsquo;, they eventually find the light that follows this, and even
accept that it is possible to have glimmers of light within the darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this essay, I will&lt;/em&gt; provide an analysis of the 5 tracks I believe provide the most depth, nuance and literary analysis, although this by no means serves do discount the remaining 7 tracks, which are extraordinary in their own right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-am-i-missing&#34;&gt;What Am I Missing?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning with the band&amp;rsquo;s 2nd song of the album, &lt;em&gt;What Am I Missing?&lt;/em&gt; describes the confusion and angst of a protagonist who feels that they
can&amp;rsquo;t move on from the parting of ways with their previous lover. Starting off the verse with a steady, synchronised drum beat and Jordan recounting how he has settled into a steady routine (from &lt;code&gt;wake up and I reach out to your side of the bed&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;I&#39;ve checked in with all your friends&lt;/code&gt;) he conveys how he is almost emotionless or running in autopilot (hense the predictable beats in the backing track).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This begins to reach a breaking point as he begins to recognise his &amp;lsquo;hate&amp;rsquo; in the pre-chorus, showing us how he is beginning to break the barrier between his numbness and emotions. The steady beat continues here until the last line before the chorus &lt;code&gt;Why am I still hopin&#39; you&#39;ll call When I know you won&#39;t?&lt;/code&gt; where he reaches self-actualisation and questions his actions upto now. This realisation is shown by the loss of rhythm and therefore the loss of a routine and control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chorus then ensues with a complete breakdown of the previous melodic structure, the movement of the beat in and out of synchopation and the barricade of bass and symbols that almost drowns the vocals out. This conveys the complete chaos and panic the lead feels as they realise their emotions follow no logic, rules or goal - much like how the backing track has been crafted to feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jordan&amp;rsquo;s raw and heavy vocals present the idea that he is almost screaming into the void, at himself and at the universe, looking for answers for his current emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;let-it-happen&#34;&gt;Let It Happen&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving onto the 4th track in the album - Let It Happen is a hard-hitting, pop-rock take on the classic &amp;lsquo;sad post-breakup song&amp;rsquo; and invites us into the narrator&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;broke-down, negative headspace&lt;/code&gt; as they regret falling in love with their ex-partner, stating that their life would have been &lt;code&gt;so much clearer&lt;/code&gt; as they admit they can start to see the beginning of their breakdown following their breakup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the song provides nuance through its alternate take on the narrator&amp;rsquo;s actions. Instead of taking their rage out through smashing cars or breaking vases, they have instead seemingly been slipping into a period of depression, through their lack of regard or care for themselves (&lt;code&gt;I&#39;ve been a little careless with my actions&lt;/code&gt;) and activies they once found joy in (&lt;code&gt;been a little passive with my passions&lt;/code&gt;). Their lack of desire has affected them to the point where they claim that if they see their previous love interest again, they will &lt;code&gt;just let it happen&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The abiguity of this line could support the theory claiming the protagonist&amp;rsquo;s depression (through conveying their current lack of feelings towards this person and therefore disregard of what happens). However, it is also possible to argue that this line hints at a small amout of optimism - they do not have any negative feelings towards the other person, they are simply indifferent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slow tempo of the backing track during the song emphasises this lack of desire - mimicing the pace at which a person may walk aimlessly down a street. The accents (the part at which the beat hits heavier idk what its called) during the chorus hint at brief moments of rage - as if the narrator is angry at themselves for feeling hopeless - but can do nothing about their current situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;save-my-life&#34;&gt;Save My Life&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up, Save My Life is the band&amp;rsquo;s 3rd song of the album and introduces the concept of duality - a key theme of the album as explained above. The oxymoronic title and lyrics (in which the protagonist boasts about risking their life to be with the person they love in comparison to the title implying the preservation of their being) indicate this. Further examples can be found within the chorus through juxtaposed lyrics such as &lt;code&gt;I can&#39;t turn you down&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Kiss me higher than I&#39;ve ever been&lt;/code&gt;,
&lt;code&gt;save my life&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;break a heart&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;only feel this alive&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;still be the death of me&lt;/code&gt; implying the light and dark can co-exist and no relationship is clear cut / black or white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also injects optimism and hope into the album (which for the last two songs, has been missing), as it suggests despite being aware of the harshness and pain the relationship may bring, they would nonetheless never turn it down. In addition to this, the chorus of voices singing &lt;code&gt;save my life&lt;/code&gt; could be interpreted to represent the number of times the narrator has made this same decision and how from experience - he has learnt it is the right choice to make.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
